        <!--Ивент 45: Кризис «евроракет»?-->
        <events45Title>"Euromissile" crisis</events45Title>
        <events45Desc autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@After the Reagan administration, influenced by conservative-militarist circles, settled in the White House, all the results of the detente of the 1970s came to naught. Our proposals to return to a policy of disarmament and reduction of global tension did not find a response from the American leadership.|@Since the beginning of the decade, the situation in Europe has continued to deteriorate. In response to the aggressive actions of the United States, we deployed several hundred medium-range missiles on the territory of the GDR and CSR and planned to increase the supply of weapons in the future. The United States then began to deploy Pershing II medium-range ballistic missiles in FRG, and also installed BGM-109G Tomahawk ground-launched cruise missiles in FRG, Great Britain, Italy, the Netherlands and Belgium.|@The Euromissile crisis has reached its climax - any further steps to deploy missiles will only lead to increased confrontation and the threat of a nuclear conflict. Maybe we should try to find common ground with the Reagan administration?</events45Desc>

        <events45Answer0>Increase the number of missiles and place them in Hungary as well</events45Answer0>
        <events45Answer1>Continue missile deployment in Eastern Europe</events45Answer1>
        <events45Answer2>Declare a moratorium on the deployment of RSD-10</events45Answer2>

        <events45Result0 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@In response to the ongoing aggressive actions of the United States and the American leadership's refusal to negotiate, we continued to deploy medium-range missiles in Eastern Europe. In addition, we announced the deployment of missiles on Hungarian territory and an increase in the supply of weapons to allied countries. The leaders of Western European countries accused us of escalating the conflict and demanded that the decision be reconsidered. </events45Result0>
        <events45Result1 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@In response to the ongoing aggressive actions of the United States and the American leadership's refusal to negotiate, we continued to deploy medium-range missiles in Eastern Europe. The leaders of Western European countries accused us of escalating the conflict and demanded that the decision be reconsidered. </events45Result1>
        <events45Result2 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@Today, the General Secretary of Central Committee of CPSU {0} gave an interview to the Pravda newspaper. In the conversation, he noted that “{1} will pursue an active and constructive policy. Considering relations with the United States to be an extremely important factor in international politics, the USSR does not look at the world only through the prism of these relations. We understand the weight of other countries in international affairs, and we take this into account when assessing the general situation in the world.”|@He also further noted the importance of Soviet-American negotiations on nuclear and space weapons, stating: “from this day on - I want to emphasize - the Soviet Union is introducing a moratorium on the deployment of its medium-range missiles, suspending the implementation of other retaliatory measures in Europe. The moratorium is valid until November of this year. What decision we make after this depends on whether the United States follows our example: whether or not they stop the deployment of their medium-range missiles in Europe.”</events45Result2>

        <!--Ивент 46: Надежный щит мира-->
        <events46Title>Reliable shield of peace</events46Title>
        <events46Desc autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@In May 1955, the Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe concluded the “Treaty of Friendship, Cooperation and Mutual Assistance,” which served as the basis for the creation of the Warsaw Pact Organization. The conclusion of the treaty was a response to the refusal of the Soviet Union and socialist countries to join NATO, as well as FRG's accession to the alliance.|@The friendship agreement was concluded for 30 years and now, because of the approaching expiration date, it needs to be extended. The upcoming event could be an excellent opportunity to provide “certain signals” to our strategic adversaries. </events46Desc>
        <events46Answer0>Continue with anti-Western rhetoric</events46Answer0>
        <events46Answer1>Continue with conciliatory rhetoric</events46Answer1>
        <events46Answer2>Let's do it without unnecessary noise</events46Answer2>

        <events46Result0 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@The signing of the Protocol on the extension of the Treaty of Friendship, Cooperation and Mutual Assistance took place in Warsaw, originally signed on May 14, 1955.|@Speaking during this ceremony, {0}, in particular, noted: “We are for reducing the severity of the confrontation between two military-political alliances, which would meet the interests of all peoples of the earth... We have repeatedly expressed our readiness to dissolve the Warsaw Pact if NATO agrees to respond same. This principled position is fully preserved. But, unfortunately, the other side did not and does not have such an intention.”|@However, {0} stated that “{1} does not consider it any longer possible to put forward any negotiating positions on arms reduction until Western countries show readiness for them". He also admitted that, in his opinion, “one should not expect such measures from the current administration.”</events46Result0>
        <events46Result1 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@The signing of the Protocol on the extension of the Treaty of Friendship, Cooperation and Mutual Assistance took place in Warsaw, originally signed on May 14, 1955.|@Speaking during this ceremony, {0}, in particular, noted: “We are for reducing the severity of the confrontation between two military-political alliances, which would meet the interests of all peoples of the earth... We have repeatedly expressed our readiness to dissolve the Warsaw Pact if NATO agrees to respond same. This principled position is fully preserved. But, unfortunately, the other side did not and does not have such an intention.”|@{0} confirmed the proposals of {1}: not to create strike space weapons, but to destroy existing anti-satellite systems, agree on a radical reduction in nuclear weapons and generally work toward the complete elimination of nuclear weapons. The first step is to freeze the nuclear potentials of both sides.</events46Result1>
        <events46Result2 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@The signing of the Protocol on the extension of the Treaty of Friendship, Cooperation and Mutual Assistance took place in Warsaw, originally signed on May 14, 1955.|@The meeting in Warsaw took place on the eve of the 40th anniversary of the great Victory over fascism. The memory of the fallen, the duty to living and future generations require us not to forget the lessons of history. “The war must not happen again!” - such is the will of millions. By extending the Warsaw Pact, the participants in the summit meeting in Poland expressed the firm conviction of our peoples: through joint efforts, war can and must be prevented. The policy of the ruling parties and governments of fraternal countries, and all the activities of the defensive alliance of socialist states, are aimed at this.</events46Result2>

        <!--Ивент 47: Звездные войны-->
        <events47Title>Звездные войны</events47Title>
        <events47Desc autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@В марте 1983 года президент Рейган объявил о начале разработки программы Стратегической оборонной инициативы (СОИ), которая предполагает создание противоракетного оружия в космосе с целью нанесения безответного ядерного удара. Экспертная группа советских ученых и специалистов пришла к заключению, что инициатива Рейгана с СОИ, скорее всего, не требует принятия немедленных контрмер, поскольку на данном уровне технологического развития реализовать ее невозможно.|@Однако генералитет считает, что данная программа со временем сможет стимулировать развитие новых военных технологий и приведет к дальнейшему отставанию {0} в области вооружений.|@Разработкой аналогичной системы СОИ интересовался еще бывший министр обороны Дмитрий Устинов. Вместе с президентом Академии наук СССР Анатолием Александровым он начал составлять долгосрочный план работ в ответ на инициативу Рейгана. Вспомнились проекты академика Герша Будкера и конструктора ракетной техники Владимира Челомея, которые ранее выдвигали идеи по созданию схожего проекта.|@В то же время, некоторые военные предлагают вернуться к выводам комиссии ученых под руководством Евгения Велихова. Комиссия рекомендовала «асимметричный ответ» СОИ, который, как считали ученые, будет стоить на порядок меньше, чем полномасштабная ответная программа.|@Но, нужно отметить, что обстановка в мире сейчас напряжена до предела и действия {0} вызовут ответные меры со стороны американцев. Стоит ли идти на деэскалацию конфликта или наши противники воспримут этот шаг как проявление слабости?</events47Desc>

        <events47Answer0>Начать разработку собственной ответной системы</events47Answer0>
        <events47Answer1>Угрожать разработкой собственной ответной системы</events47Answer1>
        <events47Answer2>Принять «асимметричный ответ» СОИ</events47Answer2>
        <events47Answer3>Выразить протест на дипломатическом уровне и обвинить США в нарушении международных договоров</events47Answer3>
        <events47Answer4>Объявить об одностороннем моратории на ядерные испытания</events47Answer4>
        <events47Answer5>Не обращать внимания на провокацию</events47Answer5>

        <events47Result0 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@Сегодня {0} заявил о начале разработки советского аналога СОИ. Уже сейчас все советские НИИ и высокопоставленные военные деятели приступили к работе, а необходимые финансы выделены в полном объеме. @|Наша программа, условно называемая «СовСОИ», реалистичнее и продуманнее американской, предусматривает вывод на орбиту новых спутников-шпионов, строительство РЛС по всей территории страны, разработку и вывод в космос спутников, вооруженных лазерным оружием. Посмотрим, как после ее реализации запоют наши «западные партнеры»!</events47Result0>
        <events47Result1 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@В ответ на провокационные действия американцев {0} заявил, что «если в дальнейшем США не откажутся от разработки СОИ, то {1} направит свои усилия на размещение вооружений в космосе».|@Иностранные СМИ негативно отозвались о советской угрозе, однако это способствовало консолидации наших граждан вокруг власти.</events47Result1>
        <events47Result2 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@Мы начали разработку «ассиметричного ответа» американскому проекту СОИ. Ответные меры предполагают следующие меры|@1)повышение уровня боевой устойчивости стратегических ядерных сил, модернизацию ядерных подводных лодок;|@2) повышение способности наступательных средств наших стратегических ядерных сил по преодолению всех эшелонов противоракетной обороны противника;|@3)разработку специальных мер по поражению космических боевых станций или размещаемых в космосе на околоземных орбитах ретрансляционных зеркал мощных наземных лазерных установок.|@Насколь успешным будет предложение советских ученых – покажет время. </events47Result2>
        <events47Result3 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@На очередном заседании Совбеза ООН представитель {1} выдвинул американцам протест против разработки программы СОИ.|@«Господин Рейган должен похоронить идею о СОИ и подтвердить приверженность США Договору по ПРО, подписанному в 1972 году. Администрация США поступает безответственно, ставя мир под угрозу новой мировой войны», – заявил советский представитель.|@В ответ американцы указали, что создание СОИ – это «внутреннее дело Соединенных Штатов», а сам проект «несет исключительно мирный характер и направлен на усиление обороноспособности страны.</events47Result3>
        <events47Result4 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@В канун годовщины американских атомных бомбардировок Хиросимы и Нагасаки, {0} направил сообщение Японскому совету организаций жертв атомных бомбардировок, где отметил важность и неотложность запрещения ядерного оружия. Также {0} объявил односторонний мораторий {1} на проведение подземных ядерных испытаний, предложив американской стороне сделать то же самое. В Белом доме пока молчат.</events47Result4>
        <events47Result5 autoNewLine="true" newLineParagraph="true">@Мы никак не отреагировал на американскую программу. Среди генералитета руководства зреет недовольство излишним пацифизмом руководства. По их мнению, опасность СОИ недооценивается. Они утверждают, что выведенные в космос платформы с лазерным оружием могут держать под обстрелом любую точку Земли. Доводы ученых, что сейчас реализовать такое просто невозможно, ими отвергаются, как «преступное самоуспокоение».</events47Result5>
